SUJITH VEDUNURI

vedunurisujith06@gmail.com | Portfolio | | GitHub | LinkedIn | +1 513-879-7129 | Cincinnati, OH

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self-motivated full-stack developer with 3+ years of experience in SAAP and the Business Process Development industry, part of a team under the supervision of the founder, determined to develop a product for Ninja Van using Go, Typescript, node.js, Next.js, React, docker, and MongoDB to build project management solutions to increase productivity.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer (Contract), Southwest Airlines, Love Field, TX, USA

Feb 2023 - Present

- Played on a vital role throughout the project's development phases as a solo contributor within an Agile setting.
- Spearheaded the migration of an outdated application from Struts to Spring MVC Framework, seamlessly integrating it with
- Hibernate; Bolstered application scalability by 50% and reduced development time by 30%.
- Automated extraction processes for various data formats using Cron jobs in shell scripting, reducing manual workload by 20%.
- Implemented Singleton & Builder design patterns to ensure the utilization of single instances and maintain modular code.
- Authored Integration & Unit test cases to ensure the isolation of functions, enhancing readability, and maintaining failsafe code
- across the CI/CD pipeline.
- Streamlined a full-stack web application using React, PostgreSQL and Docker to analyze GitHub data.

Software Engineer, Templars Technologies (Startup), Hyderabad, India

Mar 2021 - Jul 2022

- Created a PostgreSQL-backed data lake by crafting data ingestion pipelines that seamlessly integrated information from diverse business and productivity sources.
- Established essential business tools like Jira and Confluence, implementing webhooks to streamline the process of retrieving data from these sources as part of platform integration development.
- Took the initiative and spearheaded a crucial role in integrating with Airbyte.
- Implemented Redis queues, utilizing a self-consuming Redis queue to efficiently manage data consumption from connectors and
- deliver it to the backend service.
- Developed and managed a robust GraphQL schema using Hasura, enabling direct execution of REST operations on the database. improved backend response time by 30% and reduced manual query handling by 50%.
- Orchestrated the setup of GraphQL relationships between tables, optimizing data integrity and implementing role-based access controls; enhanced data security and efficiency, reducing query response times by 40%.

Associate Software Engineer, Templars Technologies (Startup), Hyderabad, India

Dec 2020 - Mar 2021

- Developed REST APIs for efficient frontend data access.
- Deployed single sign-on functionality for authorization and authentication by implementing Auth0.
- Employed React Context to effectively manage state across the entire application.
- Designed and optimized webpages in Figma, enhancing user engagement metrics and reducing bounce rate by 15%.

Mobile App Developer Intern, Roboslog, Delhi, India

Sep 2020 - Nov 2020

- Engineered a responsive mobile application using Flutter and Dart, ensuring a seamless user experience across various devices.
- Utilized Material Design principles to create an intuitive and visually appealing user interface.
- Engineered a robust logging mechanism to filter and send logs to the backend server for enhanced monitoring and debugging.
- Collaborated effectively with cross-functional teams, achieving a 90% responsiveness rate in the final application.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages/ Databases: Go, Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript, Typescript, SQL (Postgres, MySQL), Redis, MongoDB **Developer Tools**: Docker, VS Code, AWS (EC2, S3, CDNs, LB, EKS), Azure.

Frameworks/Libraries: Angular.js, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Next.js, Material-UI, Redux, Recoil, Spring boot, Pandas, NumPy, Gin, Axios, JWT, Socket.io.

Web Tools and Technologies: HTML, CSS, AJAX, Bootstrap, jQuery, GraphQL, Tailwind CSS, Next Auth, REST APIs, Message queues, PubSubs, Load balancers, Kafka, Rate limiting, Resiliency, WebSocket's.

DevOps/ Testing Tools: CI/CD, Docker, Nginx, Serverless, JUnit, Mockito, Prometheus, Grafana, Git, Bitbucket, Terraform, Kubernetes

EDUCATION

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati OH, USA

Master of Science in Information Technology (Major: Advance Storage Technologies)

B V Raju Institute of Technology, Medak, India

Bachelor of Technology (Major: Computer Science and Engineering)

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Aug 2022 - Dec 2023 GPA: 3.94/4.00 May 2018 - Jun 2022

GPA: 3.68/4.00

YouTube Lite Nov 2020 - Dec 2020

- Developed a responsive and interactive user interface for the YouTube main page, incorporating the YouTube Shorts feature
- Implemented the main page layout, including video listings, sidebars, and navigation menus.
- Added a dedicated section for YouTube Shorts, allowing users to view short-form videos in a vertical scroll format. Used mock
 data to simulate video content and user interactions.
- Utilized Recoil for efficient state management, ensuring smooth and reactive UI updates. Deployed the application on Vercel, enabling easy access and sharing of the project.
- Technologies Used: React, Recoil, GitHub, Vercel.